{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What is the main goal of penetration testing?",
        "options": [
        "To assess the effectiveness of security controls",
        "To monitor network traffic for suspicious activity",
        "To develop new security technologies",
        "To recover lost data"
        ],
        "solution": "To assess the effectiveness of security controls"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which type of malware is designed to block access to a computer system until a sum of money is paid?",
          "options": [
          "Virus",
          "Worm",
          "Trojan horse",
          "Ransomware"
          ],
          "solution": "Ransomware"
          },
          {
            "question": "What is the purpose of the Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) in networking?",
            "options": [
            "To translate domain names to IP addresses",
            "To map IP addresses to MAC addresses",
            "To establish a connection between devices on a network",
            "To encrypt data transmissions"
            ],
            "solution": "To map IP addresses to MAC addresses"
          },
          {
            "question": "In the context of networking, what advantage does subnetting offer in terms of network management?",
            "options": [
            "Subnetting allows for the efficient allocation of IP addresses and reduces network congestion.",
            "Subnetting ensures that all devices on the same network segment have identical configurations.",
            "Subnetting enables the use of multicast communication for broadcasting messages to multiple hosts.",
            "Subnetting improves network security by isolating different departments within an organization."
            ],
            "solution": "Subnetting allows for the efficient allocation of IP addresses and reduces network congestion."
            },
            {
              "question": "Which type of network attack involves flooding a network or server with excessive requests to disrupt its normal operation?",
              "options": [
              "Phishing",
              "Denial of Service (DoS)",
              "Man-in-the-Middle (MitM)",
              "Spoofing"
              ],
              "solution": "Denial of Service (DoS)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which security measure is essential for protecting against phishing attacks?",
                "options": [
                "Two-factor authentication",
                "Firewall configuration",
                "Intrusion detection system",
                "Data encryption"
                ],
                "solution": "Two-factor authentication"
                },
                {
                  "question": "In which type of learning does the model learn from its mistakes and update its parameters accordingly?",
                  "options": [
                  "Supervised learning",
                  "Unsupervised learning",
                  "Reinforcement learning",
                  "Semi-supervised learning"
                  ],
                  "solution": "Reinforcement learning"
                },
                {
                    "question": "In the context of machine learning, what is the primary objective of feature scaling?",
                    "options": [
                    "To reduce the dimensionality of the dataset",
                    "To standardize the range of features to a similar scale",
                    "To introduce additional features for better model performance",
                    "To randomly shuffle the order of feature vectors"
                    ],
                    "solution": "To standardize the range of features to a similar scale"
                  },
                  {
                    "question": "In the context of a binary tree, what is the height of a tree with n nodes?",
                    "options": [
                    "n",
                    "log n",
                    "log(n + 1)",
                    "n - 1"
                    ],
                    "solution": "log n"
                    },
                    {
                      "question": "Which sorting algorithm is not stable?",
                      "options": [
                      "Merge Sort",
                      "Quick Sort",
                      "Bubble Sort",
                      "Insertion Sort"
                      ],
                      "solution": "Quick Sort"
                      },
                      {
                        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of NoSQL databases?",
                        "options": [
                        "ACID transactions",
                        "Schema-less design",
                        "Horizontal scalability",
                        "Distributed architecture"
                        ],
                        "solution": "ACID transactions"
                        },
                        {
                          "question": "Which of the following is not a property of a transaction in a DBMS?",
                          "options": [
                          "Atomicity",
                          "Consistency",
                          "Isolation",
                          "Durability"
                          ],
                          "solution": "Isolation"
                          },
                          {
                            "question": "A company wants to deploy a web application that can handle sudden spikes in user traffic efficiently without incurring high infrastructure costs. Which cloud computing service would be most suitable for this requirement?",
                            "options": [
                            "Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)",
                            "Platform as a Service (PaaS)",
                            "Serverless Computing",
                            "Software as a Service (SaaS)"
                            ],
                            "solution": "Serverless Computing"
                            },
                            {
                              "question": "What is the purpose of auto-scaling in cloud computing?",
                              "options": [
                              "To automatically adjust the size of virtual machines based on demand",
                              "To automatically deploy new instances of an application",
                              "To automatically encrypt data stored in the cloud",
                              "To automatically update software versions"
                              ],
                              "solution": "To automatically adjust the size of virtual machines based on demand"
                              },
                              {
                                "question": "What is the purpose of digital twins in IoT?",
                                "options": [
                                "To create virtual replicas of physical devices for testing purposes",
                                "To simulate real-world scenarios and predict outcomes",
                                "To optimize resource utilization and minimize downtime",
                                "To enable remote monitoring and control of physical assets"
                                ],
                                "solution": "To create virtual replicas of physical devices for testing purposes"
                                },
                                {
                                  "question": "Which of the following scenarios best demonstrates the application of edge computing in IoT?",
                                  "options": [
                                  "Analysing sensor data in real-time at the device level to make immediate adjustments.",
                                  "Storing all IoT data in a centralized cloud server for long-term analysis.",
                                  "Utilizing a peer-to-peer network for communication between IoT devices.",
                                  "Implementing blockchain technology to secure IoT data transactions."
                                  ],
                                  "solution": "Analysing sensor data in real-time at the device level to make immediate adjustments."
                                  },
                                  {
                                    "question": "Which recent development in computer vision has enabled machines to understand and interpret visual information more effectively?",
                                    "options": [
                                    "Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)",
                                    "Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs)",
                                    "Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs)",
                                    "Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) networks"
                                    ],
                                    "solution": "Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs)"
                                   },
                                   {
                                    "question": "Which of the following best describes the purpose of the CPU cache?",
                                    "options": [
                                    "To store frequently accessed instructions and data for faster processing",
                                    "To store the operating system files permanently",
                                    "To provide additional storage space for secondary storage devices",
                                    "To facilitate communication between the CPU and RAM"
                                    ],
                                    "solution": "To store frequently accessed instructions and data for faster processing"
                                    },
                                    {
                                      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of parallelism commonly found in modern CPUs?",
                                      "options": [
                                      "Instruction-level parallelism",
                                      "Thread-level parallelism",
                                      "Task-level parallelism",
                                      "Network-level parallelism"
                                      ],
                                      "solution": "Network-level parallelism"
                                      },
                                      {
                                        "question": "Which software development methodology emphasizes the importance of self-organizing cross-functional teams and frequent customer collaboration?",
                                        "options": [
                                        "Waterfall",
                                        "Spiral",
                                        "Agile",
                                        "Prototype"
                                        ],
                                        "solution": "Agile"
                                        }
                                    

                                

    ]
  }
  